software engineering radio episode zero about.
[Music]
welcome to software engineering radio.
this is Marcus Felton.
this is episode zero.
in this episode, we will not bring you real content.
rather this is an about episode, where we'll briefly explain what this podcast is all about.
software engineering radio, or se radio for short, it's a podcast made by couple of experienced software developers and architects.
to bring you information about interesting, important and relevant topics in software engineering.
these include things such as middleware, aspect-oriented programming, object orientation, design patterns, model drama development, reflection, scripting languages, and what have you.
over time, the podcast or the episodes in the podcast we'll build a tutorial, a comprehensive tutorial.
that we think should be interesting for all professional software developers.
the normal episode will tackle a specific topic as, such as the ones I mentioned before.
and the idea is that two of our team will sit together, or get together through Skype, and discuss such a topic together.
so instead of just having somebody sitting in front of his computer and just talking boringly about a specific topic, we have a dialogue.
and this dialogue should be much more lively and much more interesting to listen to.
in addition to these tutorial kinds of episodes, will also have interviews from time to time.
with important and interesting people from the community.
for example, our first interview, that will bring in episode 3, is with Douglas C Schmidt.
Doug is well known in the community for his work on the Tao orb and the open source karma implementation.
that is widely used in mission-critical environments.
he's also a patterns book author and well known for his work in the area of modern German software development.
from time to time, we might also have round tables.
whenever a couple of us meet at a conference or some other place, we might get together and record a session just for fun.
and to discuss maybe interesting topics.
what we will not do is talk about news in the field.
such as, you know, EJB three has been released, or dotnet version C sharp three has been released.
we're not going to do a newscast.
there are other newscasts, and we think they do quite well.
we will also make sure in this podcast that there is no product advertisements.
of course it's normal that from time to time we will talk about specific products.
or our approaches that might also be associated with certain companies, like forever.
for example, if we talk about dotnet technologies, obviously it's associated with Microsoft.
however, this is not a commercial podcast.
we have nothing to sell.
so this is going to be the robot will be no advertisements and no intentional product plugs.
a standard tutorial episode will typically be thirty minutes.
interviews might be a bit longer or a bit shorter, depending on how the conversation develops. at our website.
www.rinaldin.com is about delivering the audio content.
but you will find URLs and pointers to some of the topics that were important during the discussions.
two or three words about our team.
we are a couple of experienced software engineers and architects based out of Germany.
you can find the names and our website.
so before I wrap up this first, or actually episode zero, the about episode, please let me point out that we're really interested in getting your feedback.
what you think about the show, what you think about the contents, about the format, about the people we might talk to interview.
and you can give us feedback through our comments system at the podcast website at.
this was another episode of software engineering radio.
for general information and past episodes, go to www.hsn is radio dotnet.
SE radio wants to thank Henning poly for providing the music we use in this show.
[Music]